skilledup.com 2016-05-02

# Privacy | Skilledup

###  Scope of Privacy Policy 

This policy applies to website visitors and any other user of services offered through Apollo Lightspeed LLC, a wholly-owned subsidiary of Apollo Education Group, Inc. ('Lightspeeed' or 'we' or 'our'), including the SkilledUp education marketplace website ('SkilledUp') and any other websites or mobile applications operated by or on its behalf. 

Lightspeed works with employers, course providers and subject matter experts to offer technologies and informational services. SkilledUp collects information from users interested in particular careers and jobs, helps those users explore career and educational opportunities, and provides tools for users to find and quickly assess courses that may be a good match their career interests. Lightspeed is committed to protecting your privacy and we want you to know what Information we collect, how we use that Information, and how you can request that this Information be updated or corrected. 

We've summarized the key elements of our Privacy Policy below. To read our full Privacy Policy ("Policy"), click here. 

Our policy covers any visitor to Lightspeed Site(s) and any user of Lightspeed services. This policy applies to both online and offline collection, storage, processing, and transfer of Personal Information. However, certain Lighspeed Site(s) or services may be subject to additional privacy policies (known collectively as "Additional Policies"). 

Data you disclose to Lightspeed may be shared with employers, course providers and subject matter experts that pertain to career and educational opportunities that you explore when using SkilledUp and other Sites and services. 

###  Information Collected 

We collect various types of Information through our Sites. Some Information is collected automatically through various Web and Internet technologies, including Social Networking tools used by Lightspeed to foster communication and collaboration. Other Information is collected when you provide it in response to an advertisement, a survey, or other request for information; register for or participate in other activities on the Site; order educational or other products and services; set up a Social Network or other Site profile; or use one of our career resources, assessments or other interactive tools. We may also obtain information from other sources and combine that with Information we collect about you. 

###  How we Use Information 

We will not sell, rent, or lease your Personal Information to others except as provided in this policy. 

We may collect, use, and disclose Personal Information for the following purposes: 

  * to provide requested products and services
  * to respond to your inquiries and provide customer support
  * to conduct promotions in which you have indicated an interest
  * for marketing purposes by Lightspeed and our Educational Partners, which includes, but is not limited to, sending you material about products, services, updates, etc. that we think may be of interest to you
  * to share with our Educational Partners working with Lightspeed, for the purposes of marketing their educational programs
  * for fostering communication and collaboration among users of the Sites through Social Networks
  * to analyze how Sites and services are being accessed and used
  * to improve Site and service performance and delivery
  * to prevent potentially illegal activities (including illegal downloading of copyrighted materials in accordance with our Copyright Infringement policy)
  * to analyze risk and business results
  * to maintain business records for reasonable periods
  * to enforce our Terms of Use
  * for sharing with our Educational Partners or Business Associates who are performing services on our behalf
  * to provide to Educational Partners, Business Associates or Unrelated Entities in connection with the contemplated or actual reorganization, merger, acquisition, financing, securitization, insuring, sale or other disposal of all or part of our business or assets, including for the purposes of determining whether to proceed with such transaction or fulfilling any records or other reporting requirements to such parties. In the event of any actual reorganization, merger, or acquisition such Information may be transferred as part of the transaction to the acquirer.
  * as may be required or permitted by legal, regulatory, industry self-regulatory, insurance, audit, or security requirements applicable to Lightspeed, our Educational Partners, or our Business Associates.

###  Your Rights and Choices 

#####  Marketing Communications 

If you do not wish to receive marketing email communications from us, you may express your choice where indicated on the applicable email or other communication, or email [privacy@apollo.edu](mailto:privacy@apollo.edu)

If you do not wish to receive marketing telephone calls or mailings, you may express your choice to opt-out by emailing [privacy@apollo.edu](mailto:privacy@apollo.edu). 

Under California's Shine the Light law, Cal. Civ. Code § 1798.83, we provide California residents the ability to opt out of disclosures to third parties for direct marketing purposes. To opt out of these disclosures at no cost, email [privacy@apollo.edu](mailto:privacy@apollo.edu). 

Do Not Track 

Lightspeed does not itself respond to web browser-based DNT signals. 

Other Collection, Use, and Disclosure 

You may be able to opt-out of our collection, use, and disclosure of your Personal Information in other situations subject to applicable contractual, legal or technical restrictions and reasonable notice. Note that if you opt-out of certain uses of your Personal Information, we may no longer be able to provide certain products or services. For more information on your ability to opt-out, email [privacy@apollogrp.edu](mailto:privacy@apollogrp.edu). 

#####  Other Important Information 

We will take commercially reasonable measures to secure and store your Information to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the Information under our control. 

Lightspeed may update this policy or revise it from time to time. If you are concerned about how your Personal Information is used or disclosed, you should contact us as described below or check back at this Site periodically to obtain a current copy of this Privacy Policy. 

###  How to Contact Us or Access Your Information 

If you want access or wish to update any of your Personal Information or if you have any questions about our privacy practices, please contact [privacy@apollogrp.edu](mailto:privacy@apollogrp.edu). 

**Updated:** February 28, 2014 

###  Our Privacy Philosophy 

Lightspeed works with employers, course providers and subject matter experts to provide technologies and informational services. SkilledUp collects information from users interested in particular careers and jobs, helps those users explore career and educational opportunities, and provides tools for users to find and quickly assess courses that may be a good match for their career interests. Lightspeed is committed to protecting your privacy and we want you to know what Information we collect, how we use that Information, and how you can request that this Information be updated or corrected. 

Certain Lightspeed Sites may be subject to additional privacy policies (known collectively as "Additional Policies"). In the event of any direct conflict between any Additional Policies and this policy, the Additional Policies shall control. Lightspeed reserves the right to resolve any conflicts between policies at its sole discretion. 

Lightspeed may amend or otherwise modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so please re-visit this page periodically to check for updates. The date of last revision is shown at the top of this document. 

###  Scope of Our Privacy Policy 

Our Privacy Policy covers any visitor to Lightspeed Sites and any user of Lightspeed services. This policy applies to both online and offline collection, storage, processing, and transfer of Personal Information. 

###  Contents 

  1. Definitions
  2. Information We Collect
  3. Information Collected Automatically
  4. Information You Provide to Us
  5. How We Use This Information
  6. Location of Information Processing
  7. Do Not Track
  8. Opt Out
  9. California Privacy Rights
  10. Our Security Measures
  11. Call Monitoring
  12. Internet Technologies Used
  13. Site Hosting and Links From Our Sites to Other Websites
  14. Privacy Policy Changes
  15. How to Access Your Information and Contact Us

###  1\. Definitions 

As used in this Privacy Policy, the following terms have the following meanings: 

"Business Associates" means third party service providers which Lightspeed or its Educational Partners may contract with to provide services on our behalf including those related to the Sites or for transactions occurring on the Sites including, but not limited to, Social Networking, hosting, Web analytics, lead generation, academic, business, career, or financial services. 

"Educational Partners" means a.) Apollo Lightspeed LLC's parent, Apollo Education Group, Inc., and its subsidiaries, including educational companies or institutions to which Apollo Lightspeed LLC or its affiliates may be providing educational or other related services under contract and b.) Third-parties who may participate in Lightspeed Sites and services, including employers and subject matter experts. 

"Information" means any Information collected and includes: "Personal Information", "Financial Information", "Web Analytical Information," or any other Information collected from you through our Sites. 

"Personal Information" means Information that may be used, alone or in combination, to identify a specific individual. 

"Site" or "Sites", means Lightspeed's SkilledUp Website located at [Skilledup.com](http://www.skilledup.com/) as well as other websites Lightspeed may operate, and websites Business Associates operate exclusively for Lightspeed, regardless of domain name or IP address. 

"Social Network", means various Internet communication technologies provided within the Sites that facilitate conversation and interaction between people online and includes, but is not limited to, blogs, discussion forums, wikis, chat sessions, news groups, etc. 

"Social Network Content" (or "SNC") means user-generated content you consent to share via a Social Network and includes, but is not limited to, Personal Information, digital sounds and pictures that you upload to a Social Network. It also includes your Personal Information that may be displayed on other users' Social Network pages. 

"Lightspeed", "we", "us", and "our" refer to Lightspeed. 

"Unrelated Entities" means third parties that are not Educational Partners, or Business Associates. 

"Web Analytical Information" means Internet-generated Information we collect when you visit our Sites. This Information may be linked with Personal Information. When linked with other Information identifying you personally, either alone or in combination with other Information, then such Information also will be considered Personal Information. 

###  2\. Information We Collect 

We collect various types of Information through our Sites, over the phone, through printed forms, and in person. Some of this Information is collected automatically through various Web and Internet technologies including Social Networking tools used by Lightspeed. Other Information is collected when you provide it to us voluntarily by interacting with our Sites, including Sites run by our Business Associates. We may also obtain information from Educational Partners, Business Associates and Unrelated Entities and combine that with information we collect about you. 

###  3\. Information Collected Automatically 

Each time you visit one of our Sites, Web Analytical Information is automatically gathered. In general, this Information does not identify you personally. Examples of Web Analytical Information include, but are not limited to: 

  * IP address
  * Collection Date
  * Publisher Name
  * Connection Speed
  * Day of Week Time of Day (hour)
  * Language settings
  * Country, State, DMA, City (relating to IP address, if available)
  * Domain (.com, .net, .mil, .org, .edu, etc.)

This Information may be linked with Personal Information to accomplish the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. 

###  4\. Information You Provide to Us 

In addition to the Web Analytical Information automatically collected when you visit our Sites, Lightspeed also collects, uses, and discloses Personal Information that you provide to us voluntarily in response to an advertisement, a survey, or other request for information; register for or participate in activities on the Site; order educational or other products and services; set up a Social Network or other Site profile; or use one of our career resources, assessments or other interactive tools. While the exact nature of the Personal Information may vary depending on the type of response or service requested, the following is a non-exclusive list of the types of Information that may be collected to the extent it is necessary and applicable for the intended purposes: 

  * First, Middle and Last Name, Previous Names
  * Street Address, City, State, Country, Postal Code
  * Date of Birth
  * Place of Birth
  * Gender
  * Race
  * Ethnicity
  * Country of origin
  * Employment History
  * Native Language
  * Address Type
  * E-mail address
  * Valid Day or Evening Telephone Number
  * Cell Phone Number
  * Prior Education History
  * Lead Source
  * Social Networking Content
  * Learning, Skill, or Career Assessment data
  * Career Goals

###  5\. How We Use This Information 

####  Personal Information 

We will not sell, rent, or lease your Personal Information to others except as provided in this policy. 

We may collect, use and disclose Personal Information for the following purposes: 

  * to provide requested products and services
  * to respond to your inquiries and provide customer support
  * to conduct promotions in which you have indicated an interest
  * for marketing purposes by Lightspeed and our Educational Partners, which includes, but is not limited to, sending you material about products, services, updates, etc. that we think may be of interest to you
  * to share with our Educational Partners working with Lightspeed, for the purposes of marketing their educational programs
  * for fostering communication and collaboration among users of the Sites through Social Networks
  * to analyze how Sites and services are being accessed and used
  * to improve Site and service performance and delivery
  * to prevent potentially illegal activities (including illegal downloading of copyrighted materials in accordance with our Copyright Infringement policy)
  * to analyze risk and business results
  * to maintain business records for reasonable periods
  * to enforce our Terms of Use
  * for sharing with our Educational Partners or Business Associates who are performing services on our behalf
  * to provide to Educational Partners, Business Associates or Unrelated Entities in connection with the contemplated or actual reorganization, merger, acquisition, financing, securitization, insuring, sale or other disposal of all or part of our business or assets, including for the purposes of determining whether to proceed with such transaction or fulfilling any records or other reporting requirements to such parties. In the event of any actual reorganization, merger, or acquisition such Information may be transferred as part of the transaction to the acquirer.
  * as may be required or permitted by legal, regulatory, industry self-regulatory, insurance, audit, or security requirements applicable to SkilledUp, your school, our Educational Partners, or our Business Associates.

###  6\. Location of Information Processing 

We operate or may process information in multiple jurisdictions and some Educational Partners and Business Associates may be located outside of the jurisdiction in which you reside. In such cases, your Personal Information may be collected, used, disclosed, stored and processed in these other jurisdictions for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. The data protection and other laws of the United States and other countries might differ from your jurisdiction. We require our Educational Partners and Business Associates to use your Personal Information only to perform the services we have retained them to provide and to take reasonable steps to ensure that your privacy is protected in accordance with applicable laws. Please be advised that, by using our Sites, you are consenting to the transfer and processing of your Information across international borders. Your Information may be subject to the laws of those other jurisdictions, including lawful requirements to disclose Personal Information to government authorities. 

###  7\. Do Not Track 

Do Not Track (DNT) is a browser-based signal that, when set, signifies your desire not to be tracked online. Because there is not yet a consensus on how companies should respond to web browser-based or other DNT mechanisms, Lightspeed does not itself respond to web browser-based DNT signals. 

###  8\. Opt-Out 

Marketing Communications 

If you do not wish to receive marketing email communications from us, you may express your choice where indicated on the applicable email or other communication, email [privacy@apollo.edu.](mailto:privacy@apollo.edu)

Social Networking Content 

You may change various user settings related to sharing your Personal Information contained in any user profile you set up as part of Social Network activities furnished by us. You also have the ability to delete individual instances of Social Networking Content that you have created or shared. 

Other Collection, Use, and Disclosure 

In any situation not covered by the foregoing, you may be able to opt-out of our collection, use and disclosure of your Personal Information subject to contractual, academic, legal or technical restrictions and reasonable notice. Note that if you opt-out of certain uses of your Personal Information, we may no longer be able to provide certain products or services. For more information on your ability to opt-out, email [privacy@apollo.edu](mailto:privacy@apollo.edu). 

###  9\. Your California Privacy Rights 

Under California's Shine the Light law, Cal. Civ. Code § 1798.83, we provide California residents the ability to opt out of disclosures for direct marketing purposes. To opt out of these disclosures at no cost, email [privacy@apollo.edu](mailto:privacy@apollo.edu). 

###  10\. Our Security Measures 

We will take commercially reasonable measures to secure and store your Information to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the Information under our control. 

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be completely secure. As a result, although we will utilize such measures, we do not guarantee you against the loss, misuse, or alteration of Information under our control, and you provide Information to us at your own risk. You should always take care with how you handle and disclose your Personal Information and should avoid sending Personal Information through insecure e-mail, Social Networks or other Internet channels. 

###  11\. Monitoring of Communications 

We may monitor and retain all incoming and outgoing communications for training of our representatives and for quality assurance purposes. To the extent such communications are selected, they are only retained as long as necessary to adequately discharge these purposes, unless a specific communication needs to be retained for legal reasons. If you prefer that your communications not be retained for any reason, please advise your representative. 

###  12\. Internet Technologies Used 

Cookies, Web beacons, and other relevant Internet technologies are used on our Sites to allow us to accomplish the uses set out above as well as to deliver Sites messaging and to keep track of your Information. These small pieces of program code reside in your computer and browser and can be removed. If you wish to remove such technologies you may do so, but this may render our Sites unusable to you. You can opt out of cookies or the other Internet technologies used by disabling these features in your browser program. Consult your browser's "Help" menu for assistance in changing cookie settings or removing cookie files. 

###  13\. Site Hosting and Links from Our Sites to Other Websites 

Some of our Sites may contain links to external websites hosted by Educational Partners, Unrelated Entities, and Business Associates operating outside the scope of their relationship with us. When you access such external websites, the providers of the websites may collect your Personal Information and may apply their own policies on how your Personal Information is used. In addition, some of our Sites may have Additional Policies that apply to the use of Personal Information collected on that Site. **Please make sure to read the policies of any websites you visit on the internet carefully.** Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any external websites that we do not control, and the collection, use, and disclosure of Information about you will be subject to the policies applicable on those external websites. 

###  14\. Privacy Policy Changes 

Lightspeed may update this Privacy Policy or revise it from time to time. If you are concerned about how your Personal Information is used or disclosed you should contact us as described below or check back at this Site periodically to obtain a current copy of this Privacy Policy. We urge you to review this Privacy Policy frequently to obtain the current version. Your continued provision of Personal Information or use of our services following any changes to this Privacy Policy constitutes your acceptance of such changes. 

###  15\. How to Access Your Information and Contact Us 

If you want access to or wish to update any of your Personal Information or have any questions about our privacy practices, please contact [privacy@apollo.edu](mailto:privacy@apollo.edu).
